=Love Beyond the Grave=
(Adapted from the novel by Li Qingran)
=Episode 40=
I know you've been afraid
that I'd forget you.
You aren't willing to be
the 23rd partner I've lost.
You want to be my only love.
You want me to remember you.
But you don't want me
to be stuck in the memory of parting.
Is that why
you kept silent?
I was afraid that you'd forget me.
But now, I'm afraid
that you'll always remember.
I can't forget you.
I remember everything about you.
Fireworks and lanterns.
Scent of flowers and wine.
Blood and wedding gown.
Ball and sunlight.
I remember your breath,
your heartbeat,
your pulse,
your warmth,
your scent,
your smile,
your wild talk and whispers,
your pleas and coquetry.
I don't want to forget.
I don't want it all
to fade into dust.
Foxy.
Let's get married,
shall we?
Yes.
It is time!
(Sovereign's Hall)
ظآزTouched memories linger like shadowsظآز
ظآزScattered reflections
sink into my heartظآز
ظآزIf I couldظآز
ظآزSoftly call you like thisظآز
ظآزAs gentle as a fleeting embraceظآز
ظآزEven if the day gives way to nightظآز
ظآزGrows dim and fades awayظآز
ظآزWhat would come of it?ظآز
ظآزI care for no one but youظآز
ظآزI'll come near and run to youظآز
ظآزTo heal the deepest woundsظآز
ظآزMiracles, eternity, and radianceظآز
ظآزWorth more than any barren landظآز
ظآزI might as well
spend the rest of my lifeظآز
ظآزWalking with you through eternityظآز
(The one I love is)
(natural sound,)
(frozen water,)
(blazing heat,)
(fragrant wine...)
(Sovereign's Hall)
(And precious food.)
(Black and white,)
(red and yellow,)
(he's the harmony of all colors.)
(When I first fell for her,)
(she was holding a little pinwheel)
(and twirling toward me)
(in the blazing sun.)
(In that very moment,)
(I felt this world)
(was wonderful.)
(And she was the reason)
(that made it happen.)
(She's a really, really wonderful girl.)
(She's the only thing)
(I've wished to have.)
Bound by fate,
this is a perfect match!
Bride and groom, bow to each other!
ظآزSpring comes; ice and snow thawظآز
ظآزAll things wake, with the east windظآز
ظآزIn the season at its fullestظآز
The ceremony is done!
ظآزLight the lamps to pierce the old nightظآز
ظآزBorrow mortal warmth to ease the coldظآز
ظآزWarm winds bring fragrant bloomsظآز
ظآزLet me love with all my heart
in youthful graceظآز
I'm yours now,
Your Grace.
ظآزWith you by my sideظآز
Duan Shunxi,
I'll spend my whole life loving you
and never forget you.
ظآزIn your eyesظآز
ظآزIf you'd let me know how to tellظآز
ظآزThe difference between spring
and autumn, love and worryظآز
ظآزBorrow mortal warmth to ease the coldظآز
ظآزWarm winds bring fragrant bloomsظآز
How wonderful.
Yeah.
ظآزA pot of wine in fleeting dreamsظآز
ظآزA brief life dares seek eternityظآز
ظآزBorrow one lovely dream,
let me savor this fleeting joyظآز
ظآزMay I roam drunk in dreams and
never forgetظآز
ظآزPlease ferry me once through this lifeظآز
ظآزIn the netherworld, I see a rayظآز
ظآزTo what home shall I returnظآز
It's like a dream.
Are you insane?
You gave me all five senses.
Considering your health,
you won't survive a day.
I know.
Fengyi must have a death wish.
Don't blame him.
I forced him.
Simu,
I know you write your journal
every night after I fall asleep.
The one you suspended
300 years ago.
You record daily little things
like you did before.
You put down every detail
we've shared.
That's wonderful.
I want this journal
to record more sweet memories.
To me, this world
is a present.
I want to give it to you.
With all five senses,
you can completely feel
what it's like to live.
You just can't
have a moment's rest.
Otherwise,
how could I
stir up these lifeless days
in the Void?
It's so cold here.
I already miss the warmth
of the Mortal World.
All right.
Let's go there then.
Lady Jiang Ai,
it's a perfect moment.
Get us more good wine.
Still want some wine
when you're this frail?
Give us the Cloud Wine you've treasured.
Golden sun.
The sunlight is so warm.
What's that sound?
Woodcutters have come up here.
They're singing folk songs.
What's that smell?
It's the smell of mortal life.
Would you like some?
In this world, the bride and groom
cross their cups.
This kind of life will still be blissful
even in a century, won't it?
Simu.
What do you think of this world?
It's wonderful.
Just like a home.
Your life
was full of misfortunes.
And you sacrificed your life
to give me brightness and vitality.
Do you think all these misfortunes
finally led to me?
Do you regret meeting me?
You're the only luck I've had
in my difficult life.
If life started over and over,
I would still wish to meet you.
Every time.
A thousand times.
What about you?
If life could start over,
would you still meet me?
Yes.
No matter how many times,
I would hold your hand
and pull you up
on that New Year's Eve.
I'd also hold you right now
and be with you for a lifetime.
I would be sad.
But I would never regret it.
ظآزFalling down like snowظآز
ظآزJoys and sorrows of the mortal worldظآز
ظآزSwept along by the daylightظآز
Duan Shunxi.
Don't leave.
Stay with me.
Duan Shunxi!
Thank you.
Does it still hurt?
No.
Can't you let me win once?
All right.
Duan Shunxi,
I love being with you.
ظآزLonging to meet, yet parted by destinyظآز
ظآزLet me wander throughظآز
ظآزLight and dark,┬بwithout turning backظآز
ظآزWander to the other shore
with the lanternظآز
ظآزAccompanied by eternityظآز
So...
ظآزAs all things turn and flowظآز
We've lived out this life.
So...
I stayed with you until I grew old.
Simu.
ظآزDawn and dusk rise and setظآز
Thank you.
ظآزLonging to meet, yet parted by destinyظآز
Thank you for coming back to me.
ظآزLight and dark,┬بwithout turning backظآز
Duan Shunxi.
You...
Don't leave me, all right?
Don't leave me.
Stay with me, will you?
ظآزWhether I stay or go, I'm all aloneظآز
It's all right.
It's just all right.
You'll be all right.
You'll be fine.
Simu.
Thank you.
With you by my side,
I've never lost a bet.
Promise me.
You'll remember the world as it is now.
After I'm gone...
ظآزSwept along by the daylightظآز
This will always be your home.
ظآزThe forms and hues of the mortal realmظآز
ظآزLingering for a fleeting momentظآز
ظآزWas once touched by laughing tearsظآز
Please don't.
ظآزIf I could live a simple lifeظآز
ظآزFor onceظآز
ظآزI'd be a guest in a sweet dreamظآز
ظآزDawn and dusk rise and setظآز
ظآزLonging to meet, yet parted by destinyظآز
ظآزLet me wander throughظآز
ظآزLight and dark,┬بwithout turning backظآز
Duan Shunxi.
ظآزWander to the other shore
with the lanternظآز
Duan Shunxi.
I'm here.
Don't leave me!
Stay with me!
No. You can't leave me.
I won't let you leave me.
No!
Take my hand.
Don't leave me!
Stay with me!
Who can help him?
No!
Duan Shunxi,
open your eyes and look at me.
Don't leave me.
Duan Shunxi,
open your eyes.
ظآزMoments may lastظآز
I won't let you leave.
I just won't.
Duan Shunxi.
Don't take his life!
Give him back to me!
No!
(Is this how you feel now?)
(I burned brightly throughout my life)
(and thought I'd have no regrets.)
(But in this moment...)
(Simu,)
(I'm regretting it.)
(I can't let you hurt like this.)
(I'll find my way back to you.)
Greetings, Your Grace.
From this day on,
I'll no longer command the Void.
What?
But...
But why?
The new sovereign has appeared.
Chenying has absorbed
the Lantern's power.
From this day on,
he'll be the new sovereign.
The Lantern has chosen him.
But he isn't senior enough.
Yeah. That's right.
ظآزSpirits are intoxicatedظآز
ظآزWith obsessionsظآز
ظآزForget the form to achieveظآز
ظآزYet I can'tظآز
Hail to the new sovereign!
Greetings, Your Lordship!
I think
that spirit aura
feels like Xu's.
What do you think,
Lady Jiang Ai?
He is dead.
Even if he had deep obsessions,
he wouldn't appear
before Simu, theoretically.
Yeah.
Lady Jiang Ai,
you're right.
But I believe
even if Xu is dead,
he will come back.
He'll stay with Simu.
That makes sense.
He's been like this
his whole life.
Unpredictable.
How beautiful.
Is this easy to raise?
Yes.
It only needs water.
That's good.
So many kinds.
- Take your pick.
- Sure.
Fragrant sachets and pendants.
Fruit.
Miss, take a look.
Come take a look. Fresh fruit.
(Prosperous)
Come take a look.
Sweet, I promise.
- I'll take that.
- Sure.
Come on, Miss. Take a look.
There's a new sovereign.
Since then,
she has only been He Simu.
I deeply hope
she will have happiness.
Even if this happiness
isn't perfect at all.
Hope remains anyway.
When fate permits,
the one she lost may return.
What do you think,
Goddess?
Through destiny,
all things arise.
Perhaps.
ظآزFalling down like snowظآز
ظآزJoys and sorrows of the mortal worldظآز
ظآزSwept along by the daylightظآز
ظآزThe forms and hues of the mortal realmظآز
ظآزLingering for a fleeting momentظآز
ظآزWas once touched by laughing tearsظآز
Follow me.
Don't get lost.
ظآزFor onceظآز
ظآزI'd be a guest in a sweet dreamظآز
ظآزDawn and dusk rise and setظآز
ظآزLonging to meet, yet parted by destinyظآز
ظآزLet me wander throughظآز
ظآزLight and dark,┬بwithout turning backظآز
(Prosperous)
ظآزAccompanied by the abyssظآز
ظآزMoments may lastظآز
ظآزLove and hate will fade awayظآز
(The End)
ظآزBetween black and white,
ripples crossedظآز
ظآزLight encountered shadowظآز
ظآزIt pierced the darkness and the timeظآز
ظآزThe unbreakable fateظآز
ظآزSuddenly crackedظآز
ظآزBetween black and white,
ripples crossedظآز
ظآزLight encountered shadowظآز
ظآزIt pierced the darkness and the timeظآز
ظآزThe unbreakable fateظآز
ظآزSuddenly crackedظآز
ظآزListen, all sounds are roaringظآز
ظآزAs cold ice turns into tidesظآز
ظآزA century's loneliness melts dreamsظآز
ظآزFollowing fate's guidanceظآز
ظآزBy fate, our moments were exchangedظآز
ظآزThe heart wakes up┬بall of a suddenظآز
ظآزWatch fireworks fall like starsظآز
ظآزThis bond is tangled into a threadظآز
ظآزWorldly reflections fade into mistظآز
ظآزBorrowing one fleeting heartbeatظآز
ظآزYou drew me into mortal dust,
till I'm enamored with its charmsظآز
ظآزThe heart wakes up┬بall of a suddenظآز